and today we are going to learn about
chat GPT plugins what they are how they
work internally and how we can build our
own some days ago openai announced the
support for plugins in chat GPT which I
think is going to be a total game
changer for businesses all around the
world free logins basically give charge
GPT ears and eyes they give charge GPT
access to data it has not seen before
they allow companies to seamlessly
integrate with the chat GPT interface if
they allow users to use multiple
Services just by writing a chat prompt
with that login strategypt can only
answer questions about things it already
knows about with plugins charge Deputy
can now browse the internet use other
sources of information and even take
action on behalf of the user here you
can see how after installing the plugins
the user asks chat GPT to find a
restaurant look for a recipe calculate
calories and Order ingredients instead
of providing an outdated wrong response
charge DPT uses Open Table to find our
restaurant and gives the user a link to
make a reservation it uses Wolfram Alpha
to calculate the calorie amount of the
recipe and then it uses the instacart
API to put those ingredients in a
shopping basket these my friends is a
game changer I don't know if you see it
yet but the implications of this are
enormous this basically means that Chad
DPT has an App Store now and if a
company wants to stay relevant they are
going to have to make a chat LGBT plugin
instead of going to the website or
downloading the apps of Airbnb Xperia
TripAdvisor in Amazon I will just ask
chargpt to find me a plane accommodation
the 5 best restaurants a tour guide and
to purchase me all the equipment
required to go hiking in Nepal this is
huge thanks to plugins strativity stops
being just a chatbot that answers
questions about the data it has seen
before and instead becomes an engine
interface to interact with services and
data sources in the outside world
plugins make chargpt better by
preventing hallucinations which is what
happens when chatipiti gives pretty
convincing answers that are completely
wrong this happened to me a couple of
times when I was asking it for book
recommendations and it gave me a list of
books with names authors and summaries
of books that were exactly what I was
looking for but that did not exist at
all using plugins we as users will also
be able to know what is the source of
the data that chagibiti is using for an
answer which will help us on judging if
something is true or false one of the
first plugins to be announced is the
browser plugin this plugin allows
chargeability to search on the internet
and browse websites here you can see a
demo where a user is asking about the
box office sales of this year's Oscars
movies which is something that by
default chagibiti does not know about on
the demo we can see how chargpt searches
the web clicks on links reads them and
then provides an answer with the data it
read this is amazing this really is an
important moment many many things are
about to change now that charge GPT has
basically an app store I think we will
see an explosion on Innovation the same
way we saw so many companies be born and
built on top of the iPhone and its App
Store but this also means that we have
to ask ourselves if apps websites and
custom user interfaces are going to
still be relevant in a future where
users do everything through chat GPT
rather than going to our website or
downloading our app will companies still
need to build websites IOS and Android
apps or will they just build a simple
website and put all the marketing and
Engineering efforts on building a chat
gbt plugin hosted on what will be the
App Store of open AI I think no other
group of professionals is working in
this hard to put themselves out of
business like programmers are and on
that period let's now take a look at how
you can make your own chat LGBT blogging
first you need to create an AI plugin
Json file this file needs to be publicly
accessible and hosted on the domain of
your API it also needs to be hosted
inside of a folder named that will Dash
no so if I was building a chargerbt
plugin for my website the AI plugin.json
file will be hosted on
nomadcoders.com.well known slash AI
plugin dot Json the AI plugin.json file
will have all the information of your
plugin for both humans and the AI on
this file we write the basic information
about our plugin which in this case is a
plugin that gives the users a list of
the winners of the Oscars Awards we
write down the name and description of
our plugin for both humans and the model
itself the two important things to
notice are the auth and the API part the
the oath part is where you can customize
how the user will be authenticated in
our case the authentication type is none
so the users will be anonymous but if we
want to we can authenticate the user
using token authentication HTTP
authentication or oauth authentication
as you can see the API part has a URL
key on that URL chatipity should be able
to find a file called
openapi.yamo here is where we will have
to describe to the chat GPT AI the
structure and functionality of our API
using the open API format this is the
file that chatipity will read when the
user asks a question so here is where we
explain what the endpoints of our API do
to chat GPT here you can see how we are
saying that our API has a slash Winner's
endpoint we are also providing a
description of what this endpoint does
we are telling child GPT that if the
slash Winner's endpoint is called our
API will return a list of of the names
of the Oscars winners for this year but
if the end point is called with a year
parameter like this the API will return
the names of the winners for that year
if we did a good job on describing the
API to chat GPT when the user asks
something like this chatibility will
read our open ai.yaml file it will look
through our summaries and it will decide
to call the slash winners endpoint if
the users ask something like this asking
for the winners of the Oscars on a
specific year chargpt should call the
slash Winner's endpoint but this time
with the year parameter when replying to
chat Deputy our API should not reply as
if it was a chatbot we should not reply
trying to pretend like we are cha GPT
like this instead we should reply like a
normal boring API it is chat deputy's
job to take our API response and add a
conversational layer to it as you can
see it is not that hard at all to make a
chat LGBT plugin keep in mind that we
did not write the actual code that will
get the movie's names that is something
that can be written on any language on
any server and also this is a very
simple plugin most plugins are going to
be more complex usually what you would
like to build is a chat GPT retrieval
plugin a retrieval plugin is what you
will need to build if you want to use
charge DBT to synthesize data found on
your company's documents databases
emails files slack messages
Etc to make chat DBT capable of
answering questions about your users and
your company's data a retrieval plugin
is much more complex and has more moving
Parts openai released a template of a
retrieval plugin where they explain how
it works and all the components and what
each part does I'm studying it and
working my way through it so if you're
interested on a full tutorial of
retrieval plugins let me know on the
comments overall I feel super hopeful
about Ai and what it means for
developers the fact that we now have an
app store and a new platform to build on
top of is super cool I cannot imagine
all the companies and careers this is
going to create we as developers
shouldn't be afraid of AI and the
changes it will make instead we must be
ready and open to ride the wave which
brings me to my last point if you want
to be able to ride the AI wave with me
the best thing you can do is learn how
to code now and the best way of doing it
is for free and learning by doing if
that sounds good click the link below to
learn things like JavaScript python
react react native go dark flutter among
many many others for absolutely free
click the link below to join any of our
many free courses that you can take
right now for free with me click the
link below and I will see you there
honors
see you on the next one bye
thanks